<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>talk to holly</title><description>counselling services</description><link>https://talktoholly.github.io/</link><image><url>https://talktoholly.github.io/favicon.png</url><title>talk to holly</title><link>https://talktoholly.github.io/</link></image><generator>Ghost 1.8</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 20:02:09 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://talktoholly.github.io/rss/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>What is counselling?</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Counselling is a talking therapy which allows the client to explore themselves in a safe, non judgemental and confidential environment. It provides a trained professional to be with the client to assist them in making sense of their thoughts, feelings and behaviours to understand them better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all experience some&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://talktoholly.github.io/what-is-counselling/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b1011c4db6c6300015d465d</guid><dc:creator>Holly Wootton</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 15:16:53 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://talktoholly.github.io/content/images/2018/05/jon-flobrant-1362-unsplash.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="https://talktoholly.github.io/content/images/2018/05/jon-flobrant-1362-unsplash.jpg" alt="What is counselling?"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Counselling is a talking therapy which allows the client to explore themselves in a safe, non judgemental and confidential environment. It provides a trained professional to be with the client to assist them in making sense of their thoughts, feelings and behaviours to understand them better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all experience some form of distress in our lives. It could be sadness, anger, loneliness, stress, grief, anxiety, depression or something that you can’t explain. It could be current or it could have happened in the past, or you may not know when it happened. It could lead to feeling overwhelmed or unable to cope, it could be affecting the relationships around you both personally or professionally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many things that contribute to this distress and being aware of them can help to ease the emotions connected to them. Counselling can help you do this by providing the space to explore and reflect upon these feelings. It is a place where you can begin to take control of these feelings and learn to understand them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Ethics and confidentiality</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I follow a code of ethics that are set out by the British Association for Counselling and Psychotherapy (BACP). These ethics ensure that all clients are receiving a service that is to a high standard and that I myself am following a framework which has the best interests of my&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://talktoholly.github.io/ethics-and-confidentiality/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b101159db6c6300015d465c</guid><dc:creator>Holly Wootton</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 15:15:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://talktoholly.github.io/content/images/2018/05/daniel-kim-90534-unsplash.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="https://talktoholly.github.io/content/images/2018/05/daniel-kim-90534-unsplash.jpg" alt="Ethics and confidentiality"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I follow a code of ethics that are set out by the British Association for Counselling and Psychotherapy (BACP). These ethics ensure that all clients are receiving a service that is to a high standard and that I myself am following a framework which has the best interests of my clients at the centre of it. This includes putting my clients first, working to professional standards, upholding ethics, values, principles, and personal moral qualities, respect, building appropriate relationships, integrity, accountability and candour, adhering to supervisions, continuing with training and education and responding to ethical dilemmas and issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a full and detailed breakdown of the BACP Ethical Framework, follow the link below and feel free to ask and questions you have to myself.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.bacp.co.uk/events-and-resources/ethics-and-standards/ethical-framework-for-the-counselling-professions/"&gt;https://www.bacp.co.uk/events-and-resources/ethics-and-standards/ethical-framework-for-the-counselling-professions/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confidentiality stands in each and every session whether they be face to face or over the phone. It is important for each client to feel safe in what they bring to each session and any confidentiality breaches are discussed at the beginning of the first session. It is completely up to each client what they bring to the sessions and what they choose to disclose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>What’s On Offer</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sessions on offer last an hour. The first session will be an opportunity to get to know each other and for me to answer any questions about the sessions. We will also go over the contract that will be put into place. The best form of counselling usually takes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://talktoholly.github.io/whats-on-offer/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b10113bdb6c6300015d465b</guid><dc:creator>Holly Wootton</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 15:14:21 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://talktoholly.github.io/content/images/2018/05/george-xistris-77239-unsplash.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="https://talktoholly.github.io/content/images/2018/05/george-xistris-77239-unsplash.jpg" alt="What’s On Offer"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sessions on offer last an hour. The first session will be an opportunity to get to know each other and for me to answer any questions about the sessions. We will also go over the contract that will be put into place. The best form of counselling usually takes place face to face. This is because body language plays an important role in the process. Sometimes this is not possible or desired, so I also offer telephone and Skype sessions.&lt;br&gt;
To arrange sessions, contact the telephone number provided or email hello@talktoholly.com​. Once contact is made we can discuss the initial session in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are different ways to take part in the sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Face To Face&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Sessions will be attended at a set time and venue, which will be confirmed when the sessions are arranged.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Telephone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
An appropriate time will be arranged for each telephone session and you will be contacted by myself.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Skype&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
An appropriate time will be arranged for each Skype session and you will be contacted by myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>What​ ​happens in a Counselling session?</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Counselling sessions themselves are a pre-arranged date and time and last for an hour. They provide a space for the client to bring whatever they want to talk through. They are not designed to offer advice or to guide the client in a certain direction, instead they are led&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://talktoholly.github.io/what-happens-in-a-counselling-session/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b10111bdb6c6300015d465a</guid><dc:creator>Holly Wootton</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 15:13:46 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://talktoholly.github.io/content/images/2018/05/sarah-dorweiler-357959-unsplash.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="https://talktoholly.github.io/content/images/2018/05/sarah-dorweiler-357959-unsplash.jpg" alt="What​ ​happens in a Counselling session?"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Counselling sessions themselves are a pre-arranged date and time and last for an hour. They provide a space for the client to bring whatever they want to talk through. They are not designed to offer advice or to guide the client in a certain direction, instead they are led by the client and what they want to bring to each session. There may be an issue that reoccurs or something specific which is looked at, but this is completely at the client's direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am trained as an integrative counsellor, which is several therapies combined, providing sessions tailored to each clients individual needs and personal circumstances. This allows me to get to know each client as the individual they are and provide the type of sessions that will best suite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>About Holly</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I decided that I wanted to be a counsellor after my own experience of having counselling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process helped me to find direction, allowed me the ability to take charge of my life and begin to discover what made me happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were many years before where I had felt&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://talktoholly.github.io/about-holly/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5aa6b8882a3073000187f88c</guid><dc:creator>Holly Wootton</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 17:27:43 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I decided that I wanted to be a counsellor after my own experience of having counselling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process helped me to find direction, allowed me the ability to take charge of my life and begin to discover what made me happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were many years before where I had felt a sense of being disconnected from myself, which in turn led to me not knowing what I wanted, what was best for me or who I wanted to be. The experience taught me a lot about myself and the connection between my thoughts, feelings and behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided that I wanted to train in the profession, and hopefully be able to provide for others what had worked so well for me. During my training I had two placements. The first at Red Rose Recovery in Preston, a recovery infrastructure organisation, and the second at a doctors surgery in the Stockport area. This gave me the opportunity to meet some wonderful individuals and I learnt a lot at both placements. Many clients came to me for a specific reason such as bereavement, childhood trauma, exploration of addiction, depression and anxiety, whereas others came because they were experiencing feelings of being lost or disconnected from themselves, their environment or those closest to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main thing I learnt is that counselling can be for anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Contact</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are different ways we can connect: &lt;a href="mailto:hello@talktoholly.com"&gt;hello@talktoholly.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;--&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://talktoholly.github.io/contact/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5aa6b46e2a3073000187f88a</guid><dc:creator>Holly Wootton</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 17:15:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://talktoholly.github.io/content/images/2018/03/priscilla-du-preez-181916-unsplash.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="https://talktoholly.github.io/content/images/2018/03/priscilla-du-preez-181916-unsplash.jpg" alt="Contact"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are different ways we can connect: &lt;a href="mailto:hello@talktoholly.com"&gt;hello@talktoholly.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;--&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Pricing</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Individual: £40&lt;br&gt;
Skype / Video: £40&lt;br&gt;
Telephone: £40&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://talktoholly.github.io/pricing/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5aa6b72e2a3073000187f88b</guid><dc:creator>Holly Wootton</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://talktoholly.github.io/content/images/2018/03/jez-timms-175641-unsplash-1.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;img src="https://talktoholly.github.io/content/images/2018/03/jez-timms-175641-unsplash-1.jpg" alt="Pricing"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Individual: £40&lt;br&gt;
Skype / Video: £40&lt;br&gt;
Telephone: £40&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>